TABINDA NOOR

MERN Stack Developer

- @ tabindanoor415@gmail.com
- https://github.com/Tabindanoor
- http://linkedin.com/in/tabinda-noor-935429237
- Faisalabad

EXPERIENCE

Python Programmer

Corvit Systems

= 09/2022 - 11/2022

- Faisalabad
- Worked in Python programming language to Managed the instances of AWS
- Collaboration with the team to fulfill cloud-based tasks
- Developed many complex automation scripts, increasing project efficiency by reducing manual tasks significantly.

MERN Intern

MERN Bootcamper

= 02/2023 - 2023

- Paisalabad
- Designing and implementing user interfaces for websites or web applications
- Writing clean, efficient, and maintainable code using React JS along with the Tailwind CSS. Building full stack applications in MERN, also working with firebase and react native
- Optimizing web pages for maximum speed and scalability
- Testing and debugging front-end code to identify and fix any issues or bugs
- Ensuring cross-browser compatibility and responsiveness of websites
- Keeping up-to-date with the latest web development trends and technologies
- Boosting code efficiency by 40% through component reuse and modular design.

Front-end Developer

CodSoft

- **=** 08/2023 09/2023 Remote
- During this remote internship I worked on the front end projects
- Personal Portfolio
- Blog Website

MERN Stack Intern

TopperWorld

- **m** 08/2023 09/2023 Remote
- During my remote internship, I made some projects which are:
- Flipkart Clone
- Landing Pages
- Real time applications like tic tac toe and online code editor.

MERN Stack Intern

CodeClause

- **=** 12/2023 01/2024 Remote
- Todo list in React JS
- Timer and Stopwatch
- Survey system

MERN Stack Intern

iii 12/2023 - 12/2023 ♀ Remote

- Landing Page in React
- Quiz App in React
- E-Learning App in React
- Music Player in React

Front End Developer

Thresh Tech Al

- **=** 06/2024 08/2024 remote
- Worked as a front-end developer, focusing on creating user-friendly interfaces for Al-related projects.
- Designed user interfaces using Figma and transformed those designs into React
- Developed systems for patient and doctor appointments, ensuring a smooth user experience and effective functionality.

SUMMARY

I am a Software Engineer with strong skills in web development, specializing in the MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js), and certified in Cyber Security. I have over 2 years of industry experience and love building user-friendly applications. My skills include React, TypeScript, NEXT JS and more. I am passionate about solving problems, learning new technologies, and ensuring security in digital solutions. I am hardworking, motivated, and always ready to take on new challenges.

SKILLS

NEXT JS	Javascript	Воо	tstrap	CSS	
Redux Toolkit Expre		ess JS	Express JS		
Firebase	Front-end	Git/0	Git/Github		
TypeScript	HTML5	Java	Kali	Linux	
Node JS	Node.js	Cloud (Cloud Computing		
MongoDB	React JS	AWS	S Pyt	hon	
Rest API	MSSQL	ООР	Tailwir	nd CSS	
React Nativ	e Socke	t io P	PHP F	Redux	
Software Testing MUI					
Computer Netwroking ASP.NET					

EDUCATION

BS Software Engineering

Government College University Faisalabad

GPA 3.75 / 4.0

m 09/2020 - 06/2024

Paisalabad

I.C.S and Matric

KIPS College

= 05/2018 - 06/2020 Faisalabad

- 1012/1100 92%
- Matriculation
- Govt Muslim Girls High School
- 04/2016 04/2018
- 1033/1100 94%

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

Zephrex

- Worked as a full stack developer, building both front-end and back-end parts of a web application.
- Developed a CRM system for real estate, handling client data, property listings, and user interactions.
- Held regular team meetings to discuss progress and challenges, and helped in dividing tasks among team members for efficient project management.

Software Engineer Fellow in Al projects

Headstarter

- Focused on AI projects, contributing to software engineering tasks in a collaborative environment.
- · Focused on how to use AI in Next JS.

MERN Stack Instructor

itec systems

 Delivered in-depth lessons on the MERN stack, guiding students through coding exercises, real-world projects, and software development best practices.
Provided mentorship and fostered a collaborative learning environment, ensuring practical application of concepts.

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS



Certifications And Training Bootcamps

Gemini Ultra 1.0 Hackathon 24h Claude Hackathon

Aspire leader programs MERN Stack Certification

cs50x harvard Certificate

WordSprint 3.0 Hackathon winner (ICodeGuru WPBrigade)

Microsoft C# .NET Training Certification(HCC Foundation

Cyber Security Certification

Python Programming (Stanford University Code In Place)

Software Testing Bootcamp (HCC foundation)

Powered by Shancy